Localization is all about estimating the probability distribution of the state xt,
定位就是估算状态 Xt 也就是车辆位置的
which is the pose of the car,
概率分布
another condition that all previous observations that,
前提条件是所有之前的观察
from time 1 to t,
Z1 到 t
and all previous controls u,
以及所有之前的控制
from time 1 to t, are given.
u1 到 t 都已经给定
To solve the pure localization problem,
要解决纯粹的定位问题
we assume the map is correct and does not change.
我们假设地图是正确不变的
Therefore, the map is also given.
因此 地图也是给定的
If we would like to estimate also the map,
如果我们也想估算地图
then we would solve the simultaneous localization and mapping problem,
那么 我们就需要求解同时定位和地图绘制的问题
or called SLAM problem,
简称为 SLAM 问题
which is much more complex.
这就复杂得多了
But today I don't talk about this.
但今天我们不讨论
Today, I will talk about the posterior distribution right here.
今天 我们讨论这里的后验分布
Before we go deeper into math,
在我们深入数学细节之前
I want to show you how we define
我想向你展示如何定义
the different input data for a specific 1D localization scenario.
一个特定一维定位场景下的不同输入数据
This means I will explain how the car is sensing and moving.
也就是说 我会解释车辆是如何感知和移动的
I will also show you how the map looks.
我还会向你展示地图是什么样的
This example is very similar to what you already learned with Sebastian.
这个例子和你跟 Sebastian 学的非常相似
So, let's talk about the map first.
因此 我们先看地图
The map includes the position of street lamps and trees in 1D.
这张梯度包括了一维的街道路灯和树的位置
This means we are working with landmark-based maps which are,
这意味着 我们正在处理基于地标的地图
in general, more sparse than grid-based maps.
这些地图一般都比基于网格的地图更稀疏
In the 1D case,
在一维情况下
the map is a vector of the position where these objects are.
地图是一个对象位置的向量
Here, the map includes six landmarks with the values 9, 15, 25, 31, 59, and 77.
这里 地图包括了 6 个地标 值分别为 9、15、25、31、59 和 77
For the observation we
对于观察 我们表示
state that the car measures the nearest k,
汽车测量了最近的 k
seen static objects, in driving direction.
在驾驶方向观察到静态对象
So we assume that the car can detect the distances to street lamps and trees.
因此 我们假设汽车能检测到街道路灯和树的距离
This results in an observation list which includes,
这样我们得到了一张距离表 包括
for each time stamp t,
对于每个时间戳 t
a vector of distances zt,
都有一个距离向量 zt
from 1 to zt to
从 zt 1 到
k. It is possible that we detect multiple trees or street lamps at a time stamp t,
zt k 在具体时间戳 t 我们可能检测到多个树或路灯
or detect nothing at all.
也可能什么都检测不到
The control vector includes a direct move of the car between consecutive time stamps.
控制向量包括了连续的时间戳之间的车辆直接移动
This means the control is defined by
这意味着控制是由
the distance the car traveled between t and t minus 1.
汽车在 t 和 t-1 之间行驶的距离确定的
In this case, the car moves 2 meters to the right.
在本例中 汽车向右移动了两米
The true pose of the car is somewhere on the mapped area.
汽车的真实位置位于地图上的某个地方
Since the map is discrete,
由于地图是离散的
the pose of the car could be any integer between 0 and 99 meters.
车辆的位置可能是 0 到 99 的任何整数
This means the belief of xt is defined as a vector of hundred elements,
也就是说 Xt 的信仰定义为 100 个元素组成的向量
and each element represents
每个元素代表
a probability that the car is located at the corresponding position.
汽车位于对应位置的概率
The goal is now to estimate these values.
现在 我们要估算这些值